Microsoft Patent Promise for .NET Libraries and Runtime Components 

Microsoft Corporation and its affiliates (“Microsoft”) promise not to assert any .NET Patents against you for making, using, selling, offering for sale, importing, or distributing Covered Code, as part of either a .NET Runtime or as part of any application designed to run on a .NET Runtime. 

If you file, maintain, or voluntarily participate in any claim in a lawsuit alleging direct or contributory patent infringement by any Covered Code, or inducement of patent infringement by any Covered Code, then your rights under this promise will automatically terminate. 

This promise is not an assurance that (i) any .NET Patents are valid or enforceable, or (ii) Covered Code does not infringe patents or other intellectual property rights of any third party. No rights except those expressly stated in this promise are granted, waived, or received by Microsoft, whether by implication, exhaustion, estoppel, or otherwise. This is a personal promise directly from Microsoft to you, and you agree as a condition of benefiting from it that no Microsoft rights are received from suppliers, distributors, or otherwise from any other person in connection with this promise. 

Definitions: 

“Covered Code” means those Microsoft .NET libraries and runtime components as made available by Microsoft at https://github.com/Microsoft/referencesource. 

“.NET Patents” are those patent claims, both currently owned by Microsoft and acquired in the future, that are necessarily infringed by Covered Code. .NET Patents do not include any patent claims that are infringed by any Enabling Technology, that are infringed only as a consequence of modification of Covered Code, or that are infringed only by the combination of Covered Code with third party code. 

“.NET Runtime” means any compliant implementation in software of (a) all of the required parts of the mandatory provisions of Standard ECMA-335 – Common Language Infrastructure (CLI); and (b) if implemented, any additional functionality in Microsoft’s .NET Framework, as described in Microsoft’s API documentation on its MSDN website. For example, .NET Runtimes include Microsoft’s .NET Framework and those portions of the Mono Project compliant with (a) and (b). 

“Enabling Technology” means underlying or enabling technology that may be used, combined, or distributed in connection with Microsoft’s .NET Framework or other .NET Runtimes, such as hardware, operating systems, and applications that run on .NET Framework or other .NET Runtimes. 
