<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Type Name="LocalDataStoreSlot" FullName="System.LocalDataStoreSlot">
  <TypeSignature Maintainer="auto" Language="C#" Value="public sealed class LocalDataStoreSlot" />
  <TypeSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".class public auto ansi sealed beforefieldinit LocalDataStoreSlot extends System.Object" />
  <AssemblyInfo>
    <AssemblyName>mscorlib</AssemblyName>
    <AssemblyPublicKey>[00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 04 00 00 00 00 00 00 00]</AssemblyPublicKey>
    <AssemblyVersion>1.0.5000.0</AssemblyVersion>
    <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
    <AssemblyVersion>4.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
  </AssemblyInfo>
  <ThreadSafetyStatement>Gtk# is thread aware, but not thread safe; See the &lt;link location="node:gtk-sharp/programming/threads"&gt;Gtk# Thread Programming&lt;/link&gt; for details.</ThreadSafetyStatement>
  <Base>
    <BaseTypeName>System.Object</BaseTypeName>
  </Base>
  <Interfaces />
  <Attributes>
    <Attribute>
      <AttributeName>System.Runtime.InteropServices.ComVisible(true)</AttributeName>
    </Attribute>
  </Attributes>
  <Docs>
    <remarks>
      <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
      <para>The .NET Framework provides two mechanisms for using thread local storage (TLS): thread-relative static fields and data slots. </para>
      <list type="bullet">
        <item>
          <para>Thread-relative static fields are static fields (Shared fields in Visual Basic) that are marked with the <see cref="T:System.ThreadStaticAttribute" /> attribute. They provide better performance than data slots, and enable compile-time type checking. </para>
        </item>
        <item>
          <para>Data slots are slower and more awkward to use than thread-relative static fields. Also, data is stored as type <see cref="T:System.Object" />, so you must cast it to the correct type before using it. However, you can use data slots when you have insufficient information at compile time to allocate static fields.</para>
        </item>
      </list>
      <para>For more information about using TLS, see <format type="text/html"><a href="c633a4dc-a790-4ed1-96b5-f72bd968b284">Thread Local Storage: Thread-Relative Static Fields and Data Slots</a></format>. </para>
      <para>Similarly, the .NET Framework provides two mechanisms for using context local storage: context-relative static fields and data slots. Context-relative static fields are static fields that are marked with the <see cref="T:System.ContextStaticAttribute" /> attribute. The trade-offs between using these two mechanisms are similar to the tradeoffs between using thread-relative static fields and data slots. </para>
      <para>The <see cref="T:System.LocalDataStoreSlot" /> structure serves as a local store memory mechanism that threads and contexts can use to store thread-specific and context-specific data, respectively. The common language runtime allocates a multi-slot data store array to each process when it is created. The thread or context calls various functions to allocate a data slot in the data store, to store and retrieve a data value in the slot, and to free a data slot for reuse after the thread or context object expires.</para>
      <para>The data slots are unique per thread or context; their values are not shared between the thread or context objects. Data slots can be allocated by a name or by an index number.</para>
      <para>For more information about storing local data, see <see cref="T:System.Threading.Thread" /> or <see cref="T:System.Runtime.Remoting.Contexts.Context" />. The <see cref="T:System.LocalDataStoreSlot" /> class is used with methods such as <see cref="M:System.Threading.Thread.AllocateNamedDataSlot(System.String)" />, <see cref="M:System.Runtime.Remoting.Contexts.Context.AllocateNamedDataSlot(System.String)" />, <see cref="M:System.Threading.Thread.GetData(System.LocalDataStoreSlot)" />, and <see cref="M:System.Runtime.Remoting.Contexts.Context.GetData(System.LocalDataStoreSlot)" />; it does not have any methods of its own that you need to use. </para>
    </remarks>
    <summary>
      <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
      <para>Encapsulates a memory slot to store local data. This class cannot be inherited.</para>
    </summary>
  </Docs>
  <Members>
    <Member MemberName="Finalize">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="~LocalDataStoreSlot ();" />
      <MemberSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".method familyhidebysig virtual instance void Finalize() cil managed" />
      <MemberType>Method</MemberType>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>1.0.5000.0</AssemblyVersion>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
        <AssemblyVersion>4.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.Void</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters />
      <Docs>
        <summary>To be added.</summary>
        <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
      </Docs>
    </Member>
  </Members>
</Type>