<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Type Name="IWebPart" FullName="System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart">
  <TypeSignature Language="C#" Value="public interface IWebPart" />
  <AssemblyInfo>
    <AssemblyName>System.Web</AssemblyName>
    <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
  </AssemblyInfo>
  <Interfaces />
  <Docs>
    <since version=".NET 2.0" />
    <remarks>
      <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
      <para>The <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> interface provides several UI-oriented properties that enhance the user experience of working with <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls. When you create controls that derive from the base <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> class, you get an implementation of all the properties in the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> interface, because the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> base class implements this interface. </para>
      <para>You can use existing user controls, ASP.NET controls, or custom server controls that do not inherit from the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> class as part of a Web Parts application, and they can also use these UI-oriented properties declared by the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> interface. If you place existing server controls in a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPartZoneBase" /> zone, at run time they are wrapped with a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.GenericWebPart" /> object. Because the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.GenericWebPart" /> class inherits from the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> base class, it enables existing server controls to act as true <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls and it adds to them the properties of the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> interface.</para>
      <para>If you place server controls that are not <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls in zones, they can use the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> properties at run time, and you can also declare values for those properties on server controls in the markup of the page (in page persistence format). However, because these properties are only available to the server controls at run time, design-time coding features such as IntelliSense do not recognize <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> properties that are declared on server controls. Declared properties on these controls still work when you load the page, but Microsoft Visual Studio does not recognize the properties as valid at design time. If you want to add the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> properties to existing server and user controls to enhance the design-time user experience, you can implement the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> interface in a server control. </para>
      <para>Perhaps the main reason to implement the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> interface is for controls that do not support the use of expando (custom) properties. Expando properties are strings that can be added to a class dynamically as a property, by means of the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.IAttributeAccessor" /> interface. Controls that implement this interface, including the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebControl" /> class and its children, can use expando properties. Therefore, all ASP.NET server controls, custom controls that derive from them, Web user controls, and <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls support the use of expando properties. But custom controls that inherit directly from the base <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.Control" /> class do not support expando properties. Thus, if you declare these controls within a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPartZone" />, you will not be able to declare the common <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> properties on the controls, properties such as <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Title" /> and <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Description" />. If you want to use these properties with such controls, you must implement the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> interface.</para>
    </remarks>
    <summary>
      <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
      <para>Defines common user interface (UI) properties used by ASP.NET <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls. </para>
    </summary>
  </Docs>
  <Members>
    <Member MemberName="CatalogIconImageUrl">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public string CatalogIconImageUrl { set; get; }" />
      <MemberType>Property</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.String</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Docs>
        <value>To be added.</value>
        <since version=".NET 2.0" />
        <remarks>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Web Parts applications often provide a catalog (or list) of controls that users can add to a page. The <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.CatalogIconImageUrl" /> property on a control contains the URL to an image that represents the control when it appears in a catalog.</para>
        </remarks>
        <summary>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Gets or sets the URL to an image that represents a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> control in a catalog of controls.</para>
        </summary>
      </Docs>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="Description">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public string Description { set; get; }" />
      <MemberType>Property</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.String</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Docs>
        <value>To be added.</value>
        <since version=".NET 2.0" />
        <remarks>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>The <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Description" /> property value is typically used as a descriptive string for a control in catalogs that provide lists of <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls, and as a ToolTip in a control's title bar. The content of the property appears in a ToolTip when a user positions the mouse pointer over the title text in a control's title bar.</para>
        </remarks>
        <summary>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Gets or sets a brief phrase that summarizes what a control does, for use in ToolTips and catalogs of <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls.</para>
        </summary>
      </Docs>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="Subtitle">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public string Subtitle { get; }" />
      <MemberType>Property</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.String</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Docs>
        <value>To be added.</value>
        <since version=".NET 2.0" />
        <remarks>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>The <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Subtitle" /> property is used to return a default subtitle string for a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> control that is appended to the control's title in the title bar. </para>
          <para>If you provide a default value for the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Subtitle" /> property in a control that implements the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart" /> interface, the Web Parts control set automatically appends it to the value of the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Title" /> property of the control at run time. </para>
        </remarks>
        <summary>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Gets a string that is concatenated with the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Title" /> property value to form a complete title for a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> control.</para>
        </summary>
      </Docs>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="Title">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public string Title { set; get; }" />
      <MemberType>Property</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.String</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Docs>
        <value>To be added.</value>
        <since version=".NET 2.0" />
        <remarks>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>The visible title text in a control's title bar is set by the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Title" /> property.</para>
          <para>If you do not supply a title for a control, the Web Parts control set automatically calculates a default string to use as a title. For more information, see <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart.DisplayTitle" />. Also, it is possible to provide a default subtitle that is appended to the title string. For details, see <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.Subtitle" />.</para>
        </remarks>
        <summary>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Gets or sets the title of a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> control.</para>
        </summary>
      </Docs>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="TitleIconImageUrl">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public string TitleIconImageUrl { set; get; }" />
      <MemberType>Property</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.String</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Docs>
        <value>To be added.</value>
        <since version=".NET 2.0" />
        <remarks>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>The <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.TitleIconImageUrl" /> property provides a way to associate an icon with a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> control. The icon appears in the control's own title bar. For thematic consistency, application developers might want to make this icon similar to the image that represents the control in a catalog of Web Parts controls (the image referenced in the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.CatalogIconImageUrl" /> property). </para>
          <para>As it is implemented in the Web Parts control set, the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.TitleIconImageUrl" /> property can be personalized by end users to change the image or icon that appears in a control's title bar. </para>
        </remarks>
        <summary>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Gets or sets the URL to an image used to represent a Web Parts control in the control's own title bar.</para>
        </summary>
      </Docs>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="TitleUrl">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public string TitleUrl { set; get; }" />
      <MemberType>Property</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.String</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Docs>
        <value>To be added.</value>
        <since version=".NET 2.0" />
        <remarks>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>When you assign a URL to the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.TitleUrl" /> property, the title of the control becomes a link. The purpose of this property is to provide a convenient way for end users to access additional information about a control. The additional information could provide copyright data, contact data, details about the creator of the control, or a summary of the control's purpose. </para>
          <block subset="none" type="note">
            <para>Normally, you would not use the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPart.TitleUrl" /> property to link to Help content. The best way to provide a link to Help for a control is to use the <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart.HelpUrl" /> property. </para>
          </block>
        </remarks>
        <summary>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Gets or sets a URL to supplemental information about a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> control.</para>
        </summary>
      </Docs>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
    </Member>
  </Members>
</Type>