<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Type Name="IWebPartField" FullName="System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField">
  <TypeSignature Language="C#" Value="public interface IWebPartField" />
  <AssemblyInfo>
    <AssemblyName>System.Web</AssemblyName>
    <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
  </AssemblyInfo>
  <Interfaces />
  <Docs>
    <since version=".NET 2.0" />
    <remarks>
      <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
      <para>This interface is designed to be used with Web Parts connections. In a Web Parts connection, two server controls that reside in a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPartZoneBase" /> zone establish a connection and share data, with one control acting as the consumer and the other control acting as a provider. The mechanism for sharing data in a Web Parts connection is an interface instance, which the provider serves to the consumer by means of a callback method. To establish a connection, the consumer and provider must both work with the same interface type for sharing data. If the consumer does not recognize the interface type sent by the provider, it is still possible to connect the controls by means of a transformer (a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPartTransformer" /> object) that translates the interface instance sent by the provider into a type that the consumer recognizes. For details on connections, see <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPartConnection" /> and <format type="text/html"><a href="d98cfd0f-ebd6-4871-89d5-abbd2cdef67b">Web Parts Connections Overview</a></format>. </para>
      <para>The <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField" /> interface is a provider interface included with the Web Parts control set as a standard interface for creating connections based on a data field. You can also create custom interfaces to use with Web Parts connections, but in many data-driven Web applications, it is useful to create connections based on a common row (for details, see the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartRow" /> interface), table (for details, see the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartTable" /> interface), or field from the data source, using the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField" /> interface. In a typical connection, a <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> control acting as a provider would implement the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField" /> interface and provide an instance of the interface to consumers in a special callback method. For example, the provider might implement an <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField" /> interface for a field in your user information table that contains a Web user's postal code data. Another <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> control acting as a consumer would define a special method to receive the interface instance, and could then extract the postal code data, and look up and display weather information based on the postal code. </para>
      <para>The <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField" /> interface has two exposed members. The <see cref="P:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField.Schema" /> property returns schema information about the data field encapsulated in a <see cref="T:System.ComponentModel.PropertyDescriptor" /> object. The <see cref="M:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField.GetFieldValue(System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.FieldCallback)" /> method declares a method that an implementer (such as a provider control) uses to retrieve the interface instance's field data when the callback method is invoked.</para>
    </remarks>
    <summary>
      <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
      <para>Defines a provider interface for connecting two server controls using a single field of data. </para>
    </summary>
  </Docs>
  <Members>
    <Member MemberName="GetFieldValue">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public void GetFieldValue (System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.FieldCallback callback);" />
      <MemberType>Method</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.Void</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters>
        <Parameter Name="callback" Type="System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.FieldCallback" />
      </Parameters>
      <Docs>
        <since version=".NET 2.0" />
        <remarks>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Use this method to retrieve the data field values passed by the interface.</para>
        </remarks>
        <summary>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Returns the value of the field that is being used by the interface as the basis of a connection between two <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls.</para>
        </summary>
        <param name="callback">
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />A <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.FieldCallback" /> delegate that contains the address of a method that receives the data.</param>
      </Docs>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="Schema">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public System.ComponentModel.PropertyDescriptor Schema { get; }" />
      <MemberType>Property</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.ComponentModel.PropertyDescriptor</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Docs>
        <value>To be added.</value>
        <since version=".NET 2.0" />
        <remarks>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>This property provides property information for the data passed by the interface. Transformer and consumer controls can query this property to get information about the type, contents, and other details of the field contained in the <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.IWebPartField" /> interface instance sent by a provider.</para>
        </remarks>
        <summary>
          <attribution license="cc4" from="Microsoft" modified="false" />
          <para>Gets the schema information for a data field that is used to share data between two <see cref="T:System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts.WebPart" /> controls.</para>
        </summary>
      </Docs>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyVersion>2.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
    </Member>
  </Members>
</Type>